

- Hyderabad, India 500055
- T +91 7569087634
- ✓ vamshie7@gmail.com
- Bold Profile

SUMMARY

E-Commerce Manager with proven skills in website building and social media marketing. Driven market researcher utilizes statistical analysis and sales metrics to inform process development and promotional techniques. Hard worker builds cohesive teams that boost company productivity and enhance department products.

SKILLS

- Search Engine Optimization
- Sales strategy development
- Inventory Tracking
- Competitor Analysis
- Order Fulfillment
- Online Advertising
- Sales Reporting
- Operations Management
- Brand Promotions

Vamshikrishna Eppanapelli

EXPERIENCE

September 2021 - June 2024

E-Commerce Manager The Purple Turtles Lighting Idea Pvt.Ltd | Bangalore, India

- Managed inventory levels by monitoring stock levels and ordering new items when necessary.
- Maintained accurate records of orders placed online.
- Developed a comprehensive e-commerce strategy to increase online sales.
- Coordinated with marketing team to develop promotional campaigns for products on the website.
- Managed the day-to-day operations of the e-commerce platform, including product management, website content updates and customer service.
- Provided technical support related to e-commerce issues such as order processing or product availability inquiries.
- Planned and implemented site content updates, merchandising of newly launched products, integrated campaigns and promotions.
- Planned a new content strategy which grew organic clicks by 53%.
- Coordinate the creation and launch of a new website design to improve user experience Created an online transaction system, leading to a 26% growth in online sales.
- Implemented Amazon Ad campaign with an average click-through-rate (CTR) of 22%
- Improved marketing and reporting process Shopify and Tally development and maintenance.

May 2021 - September 2021

E-Commerce Manager (Freelancer) Singhanais | Hyderabad, India

- Listed all new products across various marketplaces such as Amazon, eBay, Flipkart, Meesho, Myntra, Big Basket, and Shopclues
- Offered pricing recommendations to cross-functional teams
- Maintained current inventory and ensured all items were in stock

• Category Management

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- https://thepurpleturtles.com
- https://beruru.com/
- https://oorjaa.in/
- https://www.savedollarstores.com/

for upcoming promotions and events for marketplace partner

 Planned, created and executed digital marketing campaigns using various tools such as Google Ads Manager or Facebook Ads Manager.

March 2020 - March 2021

E-Commerce Sales Manager Realm Info solution | Bangalore, India

- Oversaw daily operations of the e-commerce platform including inventory control, payment processing and order fulfillment.
- Created new marketing campaigns to increase website traffic and conversions.
- Designed and implemented online marketing strategies that increased company's online revenue by 35 percent.

August 2018 - February 2020

E-Commerce Operations Analyst Fulfillment Centre Services | Hyderabad, India

- Worked as a seller on Amazon, eBay, Walmart, Wish, Etsy, Rakuten, Newegg, Massgenie, Notion, Groupon, Flipkart, Snapdeal, Shopclues, Vooniks, Paytm Marketplaces.
- Observed and reacted to changes in the marketplace, products, market pricing, customer preferences, and competing businesses.
- Managed the company's online product catalogue and ensured the accuracy and timeliness of product information

August 2017 - August 2018

Senior E-Commerce Product Catalogue Team Lead Deal maar Technologies Private Limited, | Hyderabad, India

- Provided leadership and guidance to team members, ensuring that tasks were completed on time and to a high standard.
- Collaborated with other departments to develop effective solutions that meet customer needs.
- · Managed accounts, sales productivity, sales reports, listings, customer satisfaction, and ratings.
- Resolved escalated customer complaints or queries promptly and efficiently.

November 2015 - July 2017

E-Commerce Product Catalogue Team Lead Bulkhouse Trading India PVTLTD | Visakhapatnam, India

 Monitored team performance against targets, taking corrective action where necessary.

- Developed strategies to increase team productivity and improve customer service levels.
- Counted inventory, resolved discrepancies and completed paperwork to keep system accurate and current.

June 2013 - November 2015

E-Commerce Executive TGS Group | Bangalore, India

- Managed website content updates to ensure accuracy of information on the site.
- Provided technical support for customers using the e-commerce platform.
- Developed and implemented e-commerce strategies to increase online sales.
- Developed a system for tracking customer orders, returns, refunds.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

March 2014

M.Tech | Electrical, Electronics And Communications Engineering Mahaveer Institute of Science And Technology, Hyderabad

May 2010

B.Tech ECE | Electrical, Electronics And Communications Engineering

Jawaharlal Nehru Technology University, Karimnagar

ACTIVITIES AND HONORS

- E-commerce Platforms: Magento, Shopify, WooCommerce, WordPress, CS Cart,Amazon Seller Central, eBay, Etsy, Walmart, Flipkart.
- Digital Marketing: SEO, Social Media Marketing, Keyword Research
- Tools: Excel (Advanced), Helium10